Hands in the air!
Don't turn around!
- Okay.
- Don't turn around!
Get on the ground!
- Hurry up!
- Give me your gun!
I said do it!
Your 2-11 pager. Now!
Put it down!
Get outta here! Go!
The driver's calling it in!
Turn it up!
Come on! Let's hurry up!
Go!
Let's go.
Come on! Come on!
It's this little cabin
in the hill country...
rustic, charming, very romantic.
- Rustic as in no running water or...
- Well, would that be a problem?
Well, when you said,
"Let's go away for the weekend"
I was kinda hoping for the kind of place
that leaves a mint on the pillow.
- Hey, Cho.
- Hey.
We have three men robbing
an armored truck.
They subdued the guard,
unloaded the cash
got out in 60 seconds.
Land speed record. Any witnesses?
They gave us approximate
heights and weights
but nothing groundbreaking.
Tactics match a team
that's been knocking off
payday loan shops around town.
But those were two-man jobs.
Well, it sounds like they made
a new friend.
Bank manager says this is the biggest
cash delivery of the year.
$600,000 in wrapped bricks.
Any tracking devices or dye packs?
They add those after the cash
is broken down.
- Lucky robbers.
- Luck is the planning you don't see.
What kinda planning?
You think someone with the bank
is involved.
Seems likely. A score this big
literally gift-wrapped?
All right, we'll get surveillance up
on the bank employees.
Well, that sounds like a hassle.
Let's just ask 'em.
Pull footage from the surveillance cameras
in the area.
Good morning. Can I have
everyone's attention, please?
Thank you. Uh, quick question...
which one of you was the accomplice
to the robbery this morning?
Sorry. Who are you?
Patrick Jane, FBI.
You?
Gil Clark. I'm the branch manager.
Did you just accuse my people?
Gil, I did. Agent Cho will explain.
Hi. How you doing?
Nice to meet you.
Sorry to hear about the robbery.
- So, what the hell is going on here?
- Just be patient, sir.
- Sorry to hear about the robbery.
- I mean, this is outrageous.
No. Not really. Not yet.
And thank you.
Well, that was my pleasure.
Uh, let me tell you something
about guilt.
It's physical...
increased perspiration, racing heart.
But when I just shook your hands
most of you were relatively
calm and relaxed
which is incredible
given the circumstances.
Except for, uh, you,
Ken Fletcher, senior teller.
Your heart, my friend,
is racing like a greyhound.
What is that supposed to mean?
And your left hand
keeps touching your pocket.
What do you got in there?
- Empty it.
- It...
Now.
Looks like a burner.
Phone you don't wanna be traced.
Who gave this to you, sir?
- I-I-I don't know. I mean, I-I...
- Answer the question.
- Who gave this to you, sir?
- I don't, I-I-I just, I-I...
Oh, no. I think you killed him.
Fainting isn't evidence of anything.
I'm hypoglycemic.
I didn't have breakfast.
My blood sugar was in the basement.
So you got the burner phone
because of your blood sugar?
You doubled the cash order
at the bank this week.
Was that the blood sugar talking?
My client is not answering
questions at this time.
I don't think Ken here,
with his health issues
is really up for prison.
So let's improve his outlook.
Start with the robbers' names.
What robbers?
I don't see any robbers.
Call me when you have somebody
in custody.
He's holding out.
He won't talk until we have the others.
Maybe we can track 'em down
with his phone.
Yeah, try it.
Know what? You run this one.
Might as well.
You'll be in charge soon enough.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
They're tired of hearing
my voice anyway.
All right.
"So, my friend has
this League of Legends team"
and they're playing a tournament
in Houston on Saturday.
I crush League of Legends.
- You wanna go?
- That'd be awesome.
I figure we could drive down
and then maybe afterward
we could stick around
and have dinner.
- Yeah.
- Really?
Sure. Let's do it.
Cool. Yeah. I'll let him know.
Hey.
Have you guys seen Jane and Lisbon?
Lisbon went to get the rest
of the security video.
Jane just said he was running
an errand.
Austin PD found the getaway car
about a half-mile from the bank,
no prints.
Tell them to dust it again just to be sure.
Anything off the phone?
Fletcher made about a dozen calls
this week
to another burner...
no way to tell who has that one.
All right.
He must have been calling the robbers.
They probably met in person
at least once, right?
That's a good point.
Can we use Fletcher's personal phone
to track his movements?
Definitely...
every location we visit
is tracked and time-stamped
on our phones.
I can use the cell tower hits
to track his path.
- How long will it take you?
- 10 minutes.
All right. Text the list
of locations to me and Vega.
We'll canvass. Let's go.
Okay.
Hey. I hear you were getting
locations for Cho.
Yeah, I just sent them.
Oh, good.
Can I ask you about something,
outside of work?
W-well, it's...
it's not totally outside of work.
You asked Vega out.
- How did you know?
- Ah, this is not my first rodeo.
- What's your question?
- I'm trying to find a restaurant.
And you wanna know
how expensive.
Well, I don't wanna tip my hand.
I think you already tipped your hand.
Okay, but how do I impress her
without coming on too strong?
Keep it casual.
Not a hole in a wall, you know?
Tablecloths, not necessarily white.
Okay.
And, Wylie?
She already said yes.
That was the hard part.
Just try to have fun.
Oh, thanks.
Wylie sent the list.
There are...
14 locations Fletcher visited.
We can cover those today.
They're all over the county.
- We wearing jetpacks?
- We'll get it done.
If you say so.
- You're definitely taking over the team?
- Yes.
Are you excited?
I don't really think about it that way.
Isn't this something you've wanted
your entire career?
- Yes.
- So be excited about it.
I am.
Oh. Good.
So, are there any changes
you're going to make
when you take over?
Yeah. A new rule.
Rookie agents are seen
and not heard.
Good luck with that.
Hey. Where have you been?
- For your pillow.
- Oh. Mints. Thank you.
I also got us a reservation
this weekend at the Alhambra.
Resort-ish style place, room service
high-thread-count sheets.
I think you're gonna like it.
You didn't have to do that.
No, I didn't, but I wanna spend
some time alone with you
and it should be at some place
that you like.
Well, are you gonna like it?
It doesn't sound very rustic.
Yeah, I'll find a tree.
Uh, this is the security footage.
Yeah, uh, could you, uh,
replay it back from the beginning
- uh, all at the same time?
- Sure.
Stop it.
That's the Alpha.
He's the one in charge.
That's what I thought, too.
He's the only one who touches the money.
Uh, you see that guy over there
with the semi-automatic?
He's the new crew member.
Uh, none of the previous robbery victims
reported heavy weaponry.
- The big gun stands out.
- Good eye.
You notice how the Alpha never turns
his back on him and vice-versa?
They don't trust each other.
The Alpha does turn his back
on the driver.
- What does that mean?
- Well, they're brothers, obviously.
Brothers?
Well, the Alpha has a limp.
It looks like he has a lift
in his left shoe.
That leg must be shorter.
And the driver has a very similar walk.
Different-size legs
is a genetic anomaly.
Brothers.
I'll go tell Cho and Vega.
Did I say you could have
one of those?
Number 4, 10 to go.
Those jetpacks sound better and better.
- Be with you in a minute.
- FBI.
I'm Agent Cho. This is Agent Vega.
Okay. What's this about?
Do you recognize this guy?
He came in for breakfast
on Sunday.
If you say so.
We get a lotta people in here
on the weekends.
Is there something wrong?
I'm busy. I have customers.
Cho.
Lisbon's text said two of the robbers
had trouble with their left leg.
See that table back there?
Look at the boot on that guy's left foot.
This is Cho.
I need backup
at 5219 Burnett Road.
Possible robbery suspects inside.
Hey, guys.
- Is there a problem?
- No problem. I just wanna talk.
Why don't we go outside?
Let's get outta here.
Let me see your hands.
Don't move.
Stay calm, everybody.
Don't panic.
- And where's the third guy?
- What third guy?
I got this one!
Go!
Drop the gun! Down on the ground!
Do it now!
"Tommy! No!"
Go! Go!
"Go! Go!"
Clear out. Get outta the way.
Call 911. Tell them officer down.
- I need to find my phone.
- Come here. Come here.
- Come here.
- I need to call it in, Cho.
No, no, no. They're coming.
They're coming.
Okay, good.
Keep breathing, keep breathing.
Stay with me, okay?
Good. Good.
All right, I just need you to calm down.
Good. All right.
Now, this is gonna hurt, all right?
I know. I know.
I know. You're okay. You're okay.
Keep breathing.
Good, good, good. Keep breathing.
- Where are they?
- Now, they're on their way.
They're on their way, okay?
- It hurts.
- I know. I know. I know.
- Just keep breathing.
- Did I mess up?
No. No, you did good, okay?
- You did good. Yeah, yeah.
- I did?
All right, now just keep breathing
for me.
Okay? Keep breathing.
Good. In, out.
Okay, you're doing good.
Hey. Hey, look at me, Michelle.
Michelle. Hey. Just keep breathing.
Good. Keep breathing.
"Hey. Michelle, look at me.
Look at me, Michelle."
Excuse me.
Is this where Agent Vega worked?
- Sorry?
- I'm Detective Brian Portis.
Austin homicide.
I've been assigned to Agent Vega's case.
- She work here?
- Yes.
I'm very sorry for your loss.
Which was her desk?
I'm gonna have to ask that nobody
touch that
- till I've had a chance to go through it.
- We know.
You know where I can find Agent Abbott?
His office is right around there.
Okay. Thanks.
I'm sorry about this.
Just a B.S. regulation.
You're not allowed to investigate
the death of your own guy.
Yeah, I get it.
We lost a man last year.
Sheriff's department took over.
It's hard.
You wanna be the one to catch
the bastards.
Point is, I know what this is like.
Want you to know
I'm here to work with you.
Okay.
The diner hostess opened right up.
The crew were regulars.
We worked the video surveillance
and ID'd the suspects.
Aaron Brunell. Goes by "Ace".
Seems to be the brains of the operation,
such as they are.
Tommy Brunell, younger brother.
He's the one got shot.
Steve Sellers.
Long sheet, lot of violent felonies.
He's the one that shot your agent.
Apologies, but I have to ask this.
Did Vega do anything unusual
this morning?
Anything different about her?
I don't know. I didn't talk to her.
Not even a "good morning".
It's okay. I'll take that for a "no".
Look, you need to understand something.
You can have the collar.
Your department can take the credit.
I don't give a damn about that.
But this case is ours.
And these men, they belong to us.
Yeah, I get it.
Good.
I'm gonna need to talk to
the agent that was with her.
Okay.
You're Cho, right?
Portis, Austin PD.
If you wanna take some time
to clean up, that's fine.
I'm okay.
Seriously, I can wait.
All right.
Detective Portis interviewing
FBI Special Agent Kimball Cho
regarding the homicide
of Michelle Vega.
Can you walk me through the events
that led up to the shooting?
Vega and I went out canvassing
a little after 10:00.
We were checking locations
where we believed the three suspects
had met up with a co-conspirator.
We'd checked four locations
when we arrived at the diner.
I identified myself to the hostess.
It was at this point that Vega
spotted two of our suspects.
She brought this to my attention.
Hey. How did it go with Portis?
Fine. Seems okay.
Okay.
Look, you know I have to make the call.
Vega's file says that her next-of-kin
is an aunt in Tampa.
- Did she ever mention anyone else?
- It's her father's sister.
She's the only living relative
as far as I know.
Okay. All right,
well, I thought I'd just check.
I'll make the call.
- You don't have to.
- Yeah, I do.
I was there. I should do it.
Use my office.
Her number's on the computer.
Ms. Vega?
This is Kimball Cho.
I'm with the FBI in Austin.
Yes, uh, it's about Michelle.
Is there any more coffee?
Uh, actually, I think we're out.
I'll, I'll make some more tea.
No. No, that's okay. I'm fine.
You don't believe
in the afterlife at all, do you?
No.
I do.
Do you think that's foolish?
No, of course not.
I just need to believe
that she's someplace.
Yeah. Yeah.
Austin PD might have
caught something.
A few minutes ago, a gas station attendant
spotted three men in a minivan
matching our description.
They were trying to buy bandages
probably for their wounded guy.
They didn't find what they needed
so they bolted.
- Where?
- Windsor Park.
Couple minutes head start
from the gas station.
They couldn't have gotten
more than a mile or so.
We'll have officers canvassing
the whole area.
- And a K-9 unit.
- And a couple birds in the air.
We might wanna institute
a shelter-in-place order.
Uh, maybe we should all
just take a breath.
We got these guys contained.
We can find them right now.
Well, or they'll see the cops
running around
and the helicopters flying,
and they'll go into hiding.
No, when you're hunting
a wounded animal
you don't just start
chasing it immediately.
- You'll drive it to ground.
- What's the alternative?
Well, no dragnet, no helicopters.
We make 'em feel safe.
Or they'll flee
and then we'll lose 'em.
Well, they're not thinking about fleeing.
They have more basic needs.
They were trying to find medical
supplies for their wounded man.
They can't go to the hospital.
We could put our people outside
local drugstores
let them come to us.
I said I'd work with you.
What do you want?
I say we go with Jane's idea.
All right. How many drugstores
are inside that radius?
A dozen.
We're gonna need some more bodies.
All right. We'll take it.
You stay back and monitor
the radio.
Sure.
It's Caldwell. I'm at location one.
This is Cho, location two.
"Lisbon, location seven."
"Abbott, location ten."
"Swafford, location four."
"Millovich, location 5."
Abbott, location ten.
I have one of 'em.
He just entered a drugstore...
1145 Terrapin.
Everybody move in.
We need eyes on all of them.
And keep it quiet.
No sirens, no lights.
Just left the drugstore,
headed south on Terrapin.
Turn the sirens off!
He knows we're here.
Brunell, drop the gun!
- Let the woman go!
- Go to hell!
Go!
Get in! Get in!
Suspects are traveling
in a gold minivan
with Texas license plates.
"They have a hostage.
Maintain pursuit."
"Do not...
I repeat, do not engage."
- They're inside?
- Yeah.
The uniforms couldn't stop them.
Drove right into the garage.
The house belongs to Susan Cofield.
Early 70s, diabetic.
We don't know if they're allowing
her access
to her medications.
She lives with her nephew, Phil.
He's in there, too.
- Has anyone spoken to them?
- Portis just did
but we don't know what they said.
He had to go talk to his superiors first.
We, we have money, jewelry.
We...
Shut up.
It's gonna be okay, buddy.
Okay? Breathe, breathe. Hey.
Sorry. Hey, hey, look at me.
Look at me.
I need you to breathe. Okay?
It's gonna be okay.
Okay. What are they asking for?
Food, a doctor for the wounded guy
a helicopter, and a pilot.
They really are just making it up
as they're going along, aren't they?
Normally we should establish trust
try to humanize the hostages but...
I don't know if that's gonna work.
I don't think these guys
have much compassion.
Well, I wouldn't say that.
It's a question of who
they have compassion for.
- These guys killed Vega.
- Sellers did, not Ace.
They're in there because he was trying
to get medicine for his brother.
That's compassion.
Should we send Tommy a doctor?
Trade that for releasing
one of the hostages?
Well, I was gonna say the opposite.
Ace is desperate. I-if we help him,
then we lose our best leverage.
Our best bet is to just
let Tommy suffer.
Sellers is in this for the money.
I mean, he'd probably
just as well let Tommy die.
Well, that's even better.
We drive a wedge between them.
Divide and conquer.
Okay. Let's try it.
Is there anything we can give 'em?
- Try anything, she dies.
- I won't.
Here.
What about a doctor?
My brother's hurt real bad.
- Yeah, you can have a doctor.
- When?
As soon as you surrender.
"Altercation with two Austin FBI agents"
"at the Tastee Pancake House."
- "Shots were fired..."
- What were you talking to the cops about?
Nothing.
We said no secrets.
I asked if we can get a doctor.
They're not gonna give you that
unless you give something up
like one of them, and there is
no way in hell I'm doing that.
He is dying.
Yeah, and it's not my fault
the dude got himself shot.
"I'm not going back to jail
to save his sorry ass."
"We agreed that we were gonna
get some help."
"Yeah, and that's before we had
a million cops on our ass."
Well, looks like it's working.
You wanted division, you got it.
Well, it's a good start,
but we need to stir the pot.
Can you hear a television on in there?
Sounds like the local news.
Probably watching their own coverage.
Excellent.
Can I talk to you?
I got a look inside.
I think if we went in,
we could take them out.
There's three armed men in there.
Things could get ugly.
- What about the hostages?
- I think we can keep them out of it.
And if we don't do something soon
they could get hurt, or worse.
- Jane says he has a plan.
- No.
He's improvising.
Now, I've followed Jane down
a lotta paths
but I'm not sure he's right this time.
You wanna go in
and take these guys out?
Is that about... payback for Vega?
Maybe.
What if it is?
Let's let Jane's plan play out
for a little bit.
In the meantime, talk to SWAT
let 'em know we might wanna go in.
Interesting.
Which of the hostage takers
are you negotiating with?
Sorry. Can't say.
Can I at least quote you
by name, Mr. Jane?
- No, uh, a well-placed source.
- That works.
"Let's go now to our reporter,
Elizabeth Kerrigan"
"who is on the scene."
"Elizabeth, what are you hearing?"
"Thanks, George.
Officially, no deal has been made."
"But a well-placed source
tells me one hostage taker"
"has started back-channel negotiations
for surrender."
What the hell?
You talking to the pigs
behind my back?
Quiet!
I don't know
what that bitch is talking about.
Trying to cut your own deal,
sell me out?
No.
Please let us go. Please.
You got something to say?
Please!
Sit down.
That's what I thought.
All right, four teams will cover
the perimeter of the house.
Alpha team will make initial entry.
- What are you doing?
- The situation is escalating.
One of the hostages was attacked.
We think he's okay,
but that may not last.
We're afraid that someone
is gonna get seriously hurt, Jane.
Just give me a little more time.
I'm sorry, Jane. We tried.
- We move in five.
- All right.
- Don't go with them.
- We know what we're doing.
- Look, you don't have to.
- Yes, I do.
Abbott and Cho, they don't wanna make
an arrest.
They wanna kill these guys.
- Other people might get hurt.
- It is not gonna go down like that.
- We'll be all right.
- Y-you don't know that.
- Lisbon.
- I have to go.
All right, you two sweep left,
you two stay center.
- Lisbon, you're with me.
- What the hell's your guy doing?
Who? Jane!
- Hey!
- Jane!
- Hey, Jane!
- Don't go in there!
- Jane!
- Get back over here!
I'm not armed.
Who are you?
- I can help you and your brother.
- How?
You have to release
a hostage first.
- Forget it.
- I-I-I'm FBI. Take me instead.
What the hell is he doing?
More valuable, better leverage.
What's stopping me
from keeping all three of you?
There's too many people
to watch.
Come on. It's a good deal.
Sellers!
Bring the crier.
- Keep your hands up.
- Oh, yeah.
Don't be stupid.
What is it now?
This guy wants to trade
for that one.
Yeah, whatever.
Okay.
I don't understand.
We were about to go in.
I am just as angry as you are,
but he's already in there.
We might as well give him
some time.
Time to do what?
He's trying to drive a wedge
between these two guys
make them turn on each other.
Look, if anybody can do that,
Jane can.
Okay.
Let's take a pause for a bit.
Half-hour.
All right.
"Honestly, I just...
all of a sudden"
"it was all of the SWAT vans
that came outta nowhere"
"and, and this is such
a-a quiet neighborhood."
"You know, we just...
none of us were expecting this."
He's clear.
You stay there.
We need to get in touch with the cops
get them to move on that chopper.
- How the hell we supposed to do that?
- I don't know.
Hey! You do not move
unless I tell you to move.
I just need to make sure
she's okay.
She's okay.
You see that bracelet?
She's diabetic.
She could go into shock.
Okay.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
How you feeling?
Scared, but okay basically.
You sure? You look a little flush.
Feeling, uh, any numbness?
- I-I'm not sure.
- How about your feet?
Y-you feeling numbness
in your feet?
Maybe a little.
That's what I thought.
I'm worried you're gonna start
experiencing loss of vision.
Your...
your breath is getting shorter.
- Oh, God.
- It's okay.
Oh. Oh, God.
- Stay calm.
- Oh, my God.
You got some trouble here.
She's about to go into a diabetic coma.
- Look, it's not my problem.
- Don't be stupid.
They have microphones in here.
They...
they have what? Where?
Everywhere. They can hear
every word we're saying.
If they think she's in danger
they're gonna come right in.
Damn it, I knew it!
Calm down, okay?
Okay, j-j-just hold on a second here.
Okay.
Look, here's what we're gonna do.
You're gonna watch him
I'm gonna take her out
the side gate.
Come on. Let's go.
Just calm down.
I'm gonna take you outta here.
Son of a...
Such a shame.
All this trouble for $800,000.
What do you mean, 800?
That's how much was taken. We got
the official count just a little while ago.
It's 600,
you don't know nothing!
- This is not my business.
- Yeah, you're damn straight!
"You got an official count?"
"I don't wanna take sides
but there was 800 grand on that truck."
"You guys took it all."
That's his plan, the money.
That's a wedge.
"You're full of it."
Doesn't sound like Sellers
believes him.
Then let's give him a reason
to believe.
"And we hear Elizabeth Kerrigan
has some additional details"
"about this morning's
armored-truck robbery."
- "Elizabeth?"
- "Indeed, Eric."
Hey, turn that up.
"We've learned it was
just over $800,000"
"stolen from the Gibbs Security
truck this morning."
"That official count from the bank"
"makes this one of the biggest
robberies in recent history."
These people need to get
their facts straight.
What?
Nothing.
I'm going to take a whiz.
Well, make it quick.
Did he say something to you
when I was outside?
No, n-not...
not much.
He just kept going on about
how he didn't wanna die in prison.
Son of a bitch. Come here.
Get away from the money!
I always knew you were gonna
stab me in the back.
Me? You're the one who screwed me.
- Where did you stash it?
- What stash?
The extra 200 grand.
- You better tell me where it is.
- Screw you!
"One of these days,
the sky's gonna break"
"And everything will escape"
"And I'll know"
"One of these days"
"The mountains are gonna
fall into the sea"
"And they'll know"
"That you and I were made for this"
"I was made to taste your kiss"
"We were made
to never fall away"
"Never fall away"
"One of these days, letters
are gonna fall from the sky"
"Telling us all to go free"
"But until that day, I'll find a way"
"To let everybody know
that you're coming back"
"You're coming back for me"
"'Cause even though
you left me here"
"I have nothing left to fear"
"These are only walls that hold me"
"Here"
"Hold me here"
"Only walls that hold me here"
"One day soon"
"I'll hold you like the sun"
"Holds the moon"
"And we will hear those planes"
"Overhead"
"And we won't have to be scared"
"Coming back"
How you doin'?
Places like this must be hard
for you.
Anyway, I don't feel like going
this weekend.
It just doesn't seem right.
- Is that okay?
- Yeah.
I can't do this anymore.
What do you mean?
I can't watch you do this work.
I mean, it...
It could've been you in that coffin.
And I don't...
I can't go through that again.
Jane.
You're the one that walked in
that house.
Yes, so that you wouldn't.
You could've died.
How is that different?
Me dying, it's-it's...
It doesn't hurt me.
You can't keep pulling me
from the path of oncoming trains.
Yeah? Why not?
Because there's always
new trains coming every day.
I'm leaving.
Now, you can come with me,
or you can stay here, but...
I have to go.
Where you going?
Someplace nice.